

# **Gerard Slee**

Architect turned VR Developer in Cape Town.

TWITTER GITHUB LINKEDIN

ABOUT ME

I am an Architect turned VR Developer with experience in design and development of Unity based VR applications for startups and large companies. I have 5+ years experience running a indie team of developers. and 6+ developing with C# and shaders in Unity. For the last two years I have been doing freelance AR and VR development, building a prototype VR DJ Experience for a startup to generate funding, and research and development of a realtime Global Illumination project for Unity using Compute Shaders. Before that I spent a few years running a bootstrapped virtual reality start-up developing games and software for architects and engineers. I love integrating new technologies and optimizing workflows and have an ability to inspire those around me. I am looking to work with people who want to drive change and alter the digital landscape and make awesome games.

**PROJECTS** 

# SuperStar DJ

Building a prototype VR DJing software. - Al crowd simulation and reaction to music, Audio Synthesizers and Mixers and Effects, Role - All Design 3D and Development of the prototype

## Lux Walker

LUX WALKER is an interactive PC and VR application that instantly converts your 3D model into a fully immersive 3D true-to-life scale model. - Multiuser (Photon) world building, Runtime 3D Loading, Realtime GI and Occlusion Culling Role - Team Lead, User Experience and User Interface, Lighting and Post Effects, All development (mostly C#) since 2017

## Live Normal

Generate Tileable Texture Maps for your Games and Architectural Renderings - Mobile App, Texture Conversion with HLSL shaders, Google Drive Integration, AWS Data Storage Roles - Entire Project, Including : design, development and deployment

# Nigiri Global Illumination

SVO Realtime GI for Unity 3D - SVO Voxel and ScreenSpace GI and Reflection Pipeline. Role - Screen and Cone Tracing, Compute and Screen Space Shaders. Trace Optimizations and Edge Filtering, UI for Editor

GAMES

# A Little Fire

A VR Camping survival Game. - A Norse Themed story with waves of enemies and simple resource management. Roles: Entire Project

# Astroid Miner VR

A VR Space RPG (Oculus Quest) with marching cube mining and randomized weapons and seeded universes - Procedural level and resource generations, Marching Cubes, Replacement Shaders, Inverse Kinematics. Roles - Entire Project

# Neon Ninja

A Neon Hack and slash advenure akin to Space Harrier - Rhythm Game with music affecting gameplay. Coverflow style music browsing. Roles - Entire Project

EXPERIENCE

# Realism Labs

CTO & Lead Developer, January 2020 - Present

# Tenebris Lab

Founder & Managing Director, Jan 2016 - December 2020

# **IXPERIENCE**

Head Teacher VR Course, Jan 2017 - December 2018

#### SAOTA VR

Built a green room and prototyped some VR games and apps with a bunch of interns with the goal of researching early stages of VR User Experience and Interaction design

## SAOTA

Candidate Architect - 3D Design and Modeling, Realtime Architecture Walk Throughs, Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

#### GMP Architekten - Berlin

Candidate Architect - Design, Rapid 3D Prototyping and Architecture Vizualisation, Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

#### SKILLS

## Languages & Frameworks

C#, Shaderlab HLSL and Compute, Others...

# 3D and Design

Hand Sketching, Architectural Degree, Sketchup, Blender, Photoshop, Indesign, Others...

#### Other

Amazon Web Services (AWS), Git, Plastic SCM

# Soft

Kind, Leadership, Intuitive, Observant, Driven

## EDUCATION

## University of the Free State

Masters of Architectural Studies (Professional) - 2014

# University of the Free State

Bachelor of Architectural Studies (Honours) - 2013

# **University of Cape Town**

Bachelor of Architectural Studies - 2008-2010

# ABOUT ME (CONTINUED)

I have been heavily focused on Virtual Reality and Augmented Reality using any tools and languages available to me. I love exploring new technologies. I am constantly creating prototypes of ideas and integrating API's in creative ways. My Architecture background means that I have an ability to take concepts through to completed products using a design orientated approach. I am very fluent in gameplay programming with c#, shader and graphics programming, uxdesign as well as management of a team. Being a board member and founder of my start up means I know how to deal with stress and how to translate instructions and progress between all parties involved with a business. I have taken concepts from design phase through deployment on multiple platforms. I am an early adopter of technology and love to explore software development, constantly on the hunt for new tools and Human Interface devices that bridge the gap between design and technology.